Inventory of the Benjamin Stoddert Ewell Papers 1784-1934
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Letters, 1784-1934. (Folder 1-19)
  - Letters: S, 1784-1934 (Folder 16-17)
    - Scott (Elizabeth S. Ewell), at Ewells, James City County, to her aunt, Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 25 November 1872. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth S. Ewell), at Ewells, to her aunt, Elizabeth S. Ewell, April 1873-March 1876., 3 items. (Folder 16)
      - Letter, 3 April 1873. (Folder 16)
      - Letter, 10 October 1873. (Folder 16)
      - Letter, 8 March 1876. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth S. Ewell), at Ewells, to her aunt, Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 19 November 1876. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (E. S. E.), at Daggers Springs, Botetourt County, Virginia, to her aunt, Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 26 July [1881]. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (E. S. E.), at Ewells, James City County, Virginia, to her aunt, Elizabeth S. Ewell, 5 August. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (E. S. E.), at Ewell, to her aunt, Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., April 1896-January 1897., 3 items. (Folder 16)
      - Letter, 1 April 1896. (Folder 16)
      - Letter, 22 June 1893. (Folder 16)
      - Letter, 13 January 1897. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (E. S. E.), at Bon Air, Chesterfield County, Virginia, to her aunt, Elizabeth S. Ewell, no date. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (E. S. E.), at Ewell, James City County, Virginia, to her aunt, Elizabeth S. Ewell, no date. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth S. E.), at Ewells, James City County, Virginia, to her aunt Elizabeth S. Ewell, no date. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (E. S. E.), at Ewell, James City County, Virginia, to her aunt, Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., no date. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (E. S. E.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to her aunt, Elizabeth S. Ewell, no date. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth) to B. S. Scott, at Williamsburg, Virginia. Postmarked Richmond, no date. (Folder 16)
    - Sherwell (Mary King), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth [ ? ], 12 August 1895. (Folder 16)
    - Slye (G. B.), at Camp Jackson, to Elizabeth Ewell, at Richmond, no date. (Folder 16)
    - Slye (Roberta) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at George Town, D.C., Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell to her daughter, Rebecca Ewell. (On same sheet.), 7 June 1849. (Folder 16)
    - Slye (Roberta) to Rebecca Ewell. Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell to her daughter, Rebecca Ewell. (On same sheet.), no date. (Folder 16)
    - Smith (C. F.), at West Point, New York, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 14 November 1838. (Folder 17)
    - Smith (Francis H.), at Virginia Military Institute, Lexington, Virginia, 3 June 1834. (Folder 17)
      Letter recommending Benjamin S. Ewell for a professorship. Statement concerning Benjamin Ewell by Thomas H. Williamson on same sheet.
    - Smith (Francis H.), at Pikesville Arsenal, Maryland, to B. S. Ewell, at York, Pennsylvania, 12 September 1836. (Folder 17)
    - Smith (Francis H.), at Hampden Sidney College, Prince Edward Court House, Virginia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia, 3 June 1839. (Folder 17)
    - Smith (Francis H.), at Virginia Military Institute, Lexington, Virginia, to Col. B. S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 31 January 1878. (Folder 17)
    - Smith (James P.), at White Sulphur Springs, to Elizabeth Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, 30 November 1865. (Folder 17)
    - Smith (R. McF.), at Nashville, Tennessee, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Ewell, Virginia, 3 October 1892. (Folder 17)
    - Smithsonian Institution at Washington, D.C., to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 17 May 1876. (Folder 17)
    - Society of Science, Letters and Art of London, to Benjamin S. Ewell, no date. (Folder 17)
      Invitation to become a member of the society.
    - Southern Historical Society, at Richmond, Virginia, to B. S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 6 September 1877. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (H.), at St. Louis, to Elizabeth [ ? ], no date. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (M. I. S.), at Jackson, Tennessee, to Thomas Ewell, at New Orleans, Louisiana, 20 December 1846. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (M. I. S.), at Jackson, Tennessee, to Thomas Ewell, at Tampico, Mexico, 5 January 1847. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (Mrs. M. I. S.), at Jackson, to her sister, [ ? ]. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (Mrs. M. I. S.), at Jackson, to Rebecca Ewell. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (Richard), at Charleston, Illinois, to B. S. Ewell, 7 June 1875. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (W.), at Nashville, Tennessee, to his sister, Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell, at Centreville, Fairfax County, Virginia, 5 November 1829. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (W.), at Jackson, Tennessee, to his nephew, Benjamin S. Ewell, 17 November 1834. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (W.), at Jackson, Tennessee, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at West Point, New York, 3 January 1835. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (W.), at Jackson, Tennessee, to his sister, Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell, at Brentsville, Prince William County, Virginia, 1 January 1837. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) [i.e., William Stoddert Ewell], to his sister, Rebecca L. Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia. Postmarked Prince Edward Court House, 29 December 1845. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to his brother, B. S. Ewell, at Lexington, Rockbridge County, Virginia. Postmarked Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia, 6 September 1848. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to B. S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia. Postmarked Buckland, 25 June 1849. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to B. S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia. Postscript by Rebecca L. Ewell, 18 December 1849. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to B. S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 28 May 1850. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to B. S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia. Postmarked Buckland, Virginia, 12 June 1850. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William), at Las Lunas, N.M., to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 28 May 1856. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William), at Fort Union, N.M., to Rebecca Ewell, 29 September 1856. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William), at Fort Union, N.M., to his mother, Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell, 1 July 1857. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William), at Fort Union, N.M., to Rebecca Ewell, 9 August 1858. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William), at Fort Union, N.M., to his niece, Elizabeth Ewell, 18 March 1859. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William), at Fort Union, N.M., to Rebecca Ewell, 3 June 1859. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William), at Fort Union, N.M., to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Bristoe [i.e., Bristow] Station, Prince William County, Virginia, 21 June 1859. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Rebecca Ewell, 12 November 1859. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to his niece, Elizabeth Ewell, 22 May 1860. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Rebecca Ewell, 12 July 1867. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Benjamin S. Ewell, 17 August 1867. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, March 1868-January 1871., 2 items. (Folder 17)
      - Letter, 14 March 1868. (Folder 17)
      - Letter, 30 January 1871. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Benjamin S. Ewell. Elizabeth S. Ewell to Anne [ ? ]. (On same sheet.), 25 January 1872. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Benjamin S. Ewell, 25 January 1872. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Benjamin S. Ewell, 5 February 1872. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William), at Lynnville, Tennessee, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 30 August 1876. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Benjamin S. Ewell, 22 November 1876. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Elizabeth S. Ewell, May 1877-November 1880., 3 items. (Folder 17)
      - Letter, 12 May 1877. (Folder 17)
      - Letter, 24 February 1879. (Folder 17)
      - Letter, 20 November 1880. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, 6 December 1880. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Elizabeth S. Ewell, 7 February 1881. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William), at Merwin, Missouri, to Harriet [ ? ], 10 December 1882. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William), at Merwin, Missouri, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 2 May 1883. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Benjamin S. Ewell, 2 May 1883. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to Rebecca Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia, no date. (Folder 17)
    - Stoddert (William) to [ ? ]., Two letters. incomplete (Folder 17)
    - Stone (E. W.), at Headquarters First Military District, State of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia, to James Simons, president of the board of directors, Eastern Lunatic Asylum, State of Virginia, 9 October 1868. (Folder 17)
      Copy of the order appointing Benjamin S. Ewell to the board of directors of the Eastern Lunatic Asylum.
    - Sweet (Drew), at Waynesville, Ohio, to Col. Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 15 May 1887. (Folder 17)
  - Letters: T-Z, 1784-1934 (Folder 18)
    - Taliaferro (John), at Washington, to B. S. Ewell, at York, Pennsylvania, 28 April 1838. (Folder 18)
    - Thomas (J. A.), at West Point, New York, to the Trustees of Columbia College, South Carolina, 8 November 1838. (Folder 18)
    - Ticknor (George) to Professor B. S. Ewell, no date. (Folder 18)
    - Toner (J. M.), at Washington, D.C., to B. S. Ewell, 30 August 1889. (Folder 18)
    - Trimble (I.) to B. S. Ewell, May 1835-April 1839., 3 items. (Folder 18)
      - Trimble (I.), at Newport, Rhode Island, to B. S. Ewell, 13 September 1839. (Folder 18)
      - Trimble (Isaac), at Baltimore, Maryland, to B. S. Ewell, at West Point, New York, 19 May [1835]. (Folder 18)
      - Trimble (Isaac), at Baltimore, Maryland, to B. S. Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia, 28 April [1839]. (Folder 18)
    - Truehart (A. F.) to Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell, at William and Mary College, Williamsburg, Virginia, 6 November 1857. (Folder 18)
    - Tucker (J. R.), at Lexington, Virginia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 26 July 1872. (Folder 18)
    - Turner (Harriot S.), at Richmond, to Elizabeth Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, 16 August 1864. (Folder 18)
    - Turner (Harriot S.) to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, 31 January [1872]. (Folder 18)
    - Turner (Harriot S.), at Normandy, to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, 27 February 1872. (Folder 18)
    - Turner (Harriot S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Major C. Brown, at Spring Hill, Maury County, Tennessee, 7 July 1885. (Folder 18)
    - Turner (Harriot S.) to Elizabeth Ewell, sister of Benjamin S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., no date. (Folder 18)
    - Turner (Harriot S.), at Normandy, Missouri, to Elizabeth Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., undated., Two letters. (Folder 18)
    - Turner (Harriot S.) to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, undated., Two letters. (Folder 18)
    - Turner (Harriot S.), at Marietta, Missouri, to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, undated., Two letters. (Folder 18)
    - Turner (Harriot S.), at Normandy, Missouri, to Elizabeth Ewell Scott. (Folder 18)
    - Turner (Harriot S.), at Marietta, Missouri, to Mrs. Beverly Scott, at Richmond, Virginia. (Folder 18)
    - Turner (Harriot S.), at Washington, D.C., to Dr. [ ? ] Wise. (See William and Mary College Papers.) (Folder 18)
    - Turner (Harriot S.) to Dr. Wise. (See William and Mary College Papers.) (Folder 18)
    - Tyler (John) [president of the United States], at Villa Margaret, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia. Postmarked Hampton, Virginia, 6 September 1859. (Folder 18)
    - Tyler (John) [son of the president], at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Col. B. S. Ewell, 16 November 1880. (Folder 18)
    - Tyler (John) to James A. Garfield, 24 December 1880. (Folder 18)
    - Tyler (John), at Washington, D.C., to Col. Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 17 February 1887. (Folder 18)
    - Tyler (Julia Gardiner), at Richmond, Virginia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 26 September 1882. (Folder 18)
    - Tyler (Lyon G.), at Richmond, Virginia, to Col. Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 17 March 1886. (Folder 18)
    - Tyler (Lyon G.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Bessie [ ? ], 11 October 1905. (Folder 18)
    - United States, War Department, Commission on training camp activities, to Mrs. R. M. Crawford, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 27 November 1918. (Folder 18)
    - Venable (W. E.), at Longwood, to Professor Ewell, at Hampden Sidney College, Prince Edward County, Virginia, 15 February 1841. (Folder 18)
    - Vinter (Francis), at Trinity Parish, New York, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 21 September 1859. (Folder 18)
    - Virginia Historical Society, at Richmond, Virginia, to Col. B. S. Ewell, 6 August 1881. (Folder 18)
      Certificate of election to membership in the Society.
    - Ward (Artemus), at Baltimore, Maryland, to Betsy Jane Ward, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 2 December 1865. (Folder 18)
    - Washington, Henry A., at Campbellton, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 22 June 1851. (Folder 18)
    - Watkins (F. N.), at Hampden Sidney College, to the Visitors of the William and Mary University, 7 April 1848. (Folder 18)
    - West (Robert), at North East P.O., Cecil County, Maryland, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 8 April 1866. (Folder 18)
    - Whitner (J. H.), at Rose Hill, to [ ? ], 1 August 1865. (Folder 18)
    - Wise (Henry A.), at Richmond, Virginia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, August 1870., 3 items. (Folder 18)
      - Letter, 2 August 1870. (Folder 18)
      - Letter, 3 August 1870. (Folder 18)
      - Letter, 12 August 1870. (Folder 18)
        Enclosure: Three sheets of data on farming.
    - Wood[?] (J. R.), at New York, to [ ? ], 1 February 1866. (Folder 18)
    - Wyatt (Charles B.), at San Francisco, California, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 8 April 1869. (Folder 18)
  - Letters from unknown persons, 1784-1934 (Folder 19)
    - Letters from unknown persons to Benjamin S. Ewell, February 1838-December 1846., 4 items. (Folder 19)
      - Upper Marlboro, [Maryland], to York, Pennsylvania, 21 February 1838. (Folder 19)
      - Frankfort, Kentucky, 15 October 1839. (Folder 19)
        An incomplete letter concerning a professorship at Transylvania University.
      - Postmarked Prince Edward Court House, [Virginia] to Lexington, Virginia, 15 December 1846. (Folder 19)
      - Postmarked Greenwich, Virginia to West Point, New York, no date. (Folder 19)
    - Letters from unknown persons to Elizabeth Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, August 1863-January 1868., 16 items. (Folder 19)
      - Letter signed: Aunt Lizzie, 15 August 1863. (Folder 19)
      - Letter, 9 April 1864. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Richmond, 18 July 1864. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from York, Pennsylvania, signed: Aunt Sarah [McIlvainez], 28 April 1865. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Richmond, signed: Aunt Lizzie, 7 August 1865. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Richmond, signed: Aunt Lizzie, 26 September 1865. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Richmond, signed: Mamie, November 1865. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Richmond, signed: Aunt Lizzie, 23 March 1866. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Richmond, signed: "Mama", 16 April 1866. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Richmond, signed: "Maymay", 30 May 1866. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Washington, signed: Bee, 25 October 1866. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Richmond, signed: Mamie, 19 December 1867. (Folder 19)
        Enclosure: A pencil drawing entitled "Mary's new walking dress."
      - Letter written from Cokesbury, signed: Charlotte, 28 January 1868. (Folder 19)
      - One letter signed: Aunt Lizzie. (Folder 19)
      - Letters written from St. Louis to Richmond., 2 items. (Folder 19)
      - Letters., 3 items. Unsigned. (Folder 19)
    - Letters from unknown persons to Rebecca Ewell, July 1852-March 1862., 2 items. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Georgetown, signed: Matilda, 9 July 1852. (Folder 19)
      - Letter, 22 March 1862. (Folder 19)
    - An undated letter from an unknown person to William Stoddert, at Richmond, Virginia. (Folder 19)
    - Letters to unknown persons, October 1805-January 1899., 5 items. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Philadelphia, 12 October 1805. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from [Prince George County] from Agnes to Aunt Sallie, 7 April 1856. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Jackson, 27 December 1885. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Havana, Cuba, 20 January 1899. (Folder 19)
      - Letter written from Bel Air, no date. (Folder 19)
    - Unidentified and incomplete letters., 12 items. (Folder 19)
  Series 2: Papers
- Papers 1784-1934. (Folder 20-24)
  - Brown (Campbell), 1862-1885. (Folder 20)
    - Ewell's Division at Front Royal, 1862., 1 item. (Folder 20)
      First draft of the article on the first battle of Winchester.
    - The First Manassas, 1885., 1 item. 8 pages. 23 cm. Printed pamphlet. (Folder 20)
      Correspondence between Generals R. S. Ewell and G. T. Beauregard, to which are added extracts from a letter of Gen. Fitz Lee. Nashville, Tennessee, Wheeler, Osburn, and Duckworth.
  - Crawford (Mrs. R.M.), no date., 1 item. (Folder 20)
    Rough draft of an address made before the city council of Williamsburg, Virginia.
  - Ewell (Benjamin S.), 1860-1895. (Folder 20)
    - Return of Captain Henry D. Dickerson's Company, 32nd Regiment of Virginia Volunteers, C.S.A. (Colonel Benjamin S. Ewell) for the month of July 1860. (See Tucker Papers.), July 1860. (Folder 20)
    - Certificate of appointment of Benjamin S. Ewell as Major in the Active Volunteer Forces of the State [of Virginia], 2 May 1861., 1 item. Signed John Letcher. (Folder 20)
    - Certificate of appointment of Benjamin S. Ewell as Colonel in the Active Volunteer Forces of the State [of Virginia], 27 June 1861., 1 item. Signed John Letcher. (Folder 20)
    - Letter from Benjamin S. Ewell, 6 July 1861., 1 item. (Folder 20)
      The letter acknowledges his promotion to the rank of colonel in the Virginia Volunteers and gives a copy of an order to muster six companies of volunteers from James City and the adjoining counties and a list of companies mustered.
    - Certificate of appointment of Benjamin S. Ewell as colonel, Adjutant General's Department, C.S.A., 24 November 1862., 1 item. Signed James A. Sedden. (Folder 20)
    - Statement of property belonging to or managed by Benjamin S. Ewell, 12 December 1868., 1 item. (Folder 20)
    - Certificate of appointment of Col. Benjamin S. Ewell, Col. Randolph Harrison, and Capt. R. A. Wise as examiners under an act to provide for the reorganization of the militia for Williamsburg and James City County, 24 July 1871., 1 item. Signed Gilbert C. Walker. (Folder 20)
    - Will of Benjamin S. Ewell, 10 December 1873., 1 item. (Folder 20)
    - Certificate of election of Benjamin S. Ewell as an honorary member of the Royal Historical Society of Great Britain, 4 November 1880., 1 item. (Folder 20)
    - Deed from Benjamin S. Ewell to John B. Fitzgerald and W. B. Breen, covering a portion of the Rock Smith Farm in Prince William County, Virginia, 15 December 1883., 1 item. (Folder 20)
    - An act to establish a normal school at William and Mary College, 19 March 1888., 1 item. (Folder 20)
    - Report by Benjamin S. Ewell, executor, on the estate of his mother, Mrs. Elizabeth S. Ewell, 10 September 1888., 1 item. (Folder 20)
    - Resolution of the alumni association of William and Mary College, upon the death of Benjamin S. Ewell, 1 October 1894. (Folder 20)
    - A circular letter from Benjamin S. Ewell, Lt. Col. of Virginia Volunteers, to the citizens of James City, York, and Warwick Counties, asking for labor and implements for the construction of defenses on the peninsula, [1862]., 1 item. (Folder 20)
    - Notes on General John Magruder by Benjamin S. Ewell., 1 item. (Folder 20)
    - Reminisces of General Magruder and events around Williamsburg, written by Benjamin S. Ewell for the Magruder-Ewell Camp of Confederate Veterans., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 20)
    - Notes on Mexico by Benjamin S. Ewell., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 20)
    - Notes on the origin of Virginia Counties, by B. S. Ewell. (Folder 20)
    - Notes on General Joseph E. Johnston and General Robert E. Lee., 1 item. (Folder 20)
    - Two pages from a report of Benjamin S. Ewell as president of William and Mary College. (Folder 20)
    - Page 17 of a report by Benjamin S. Ewell as president of William and Mary College. (Folder 20)
    - Page 19 of a paper concerning the establishment of a normal college. (Folder 20)
    - Printed card containing information about William and Mary College., 1 item. (Folder 20)
    - Black certificate of proficiency. College of William and Mary. (Folder 20)
    - Accounts, invoices, and checks of Benjamin S. Ewell., 30 items. (Folder 20)
    - Benjamin S. Ewell [A tribute by E. J. Harvie], 1895. (Folder 20)
    - Photograph of Malachi Gardner, carriage driver of Benjamin S. Ewell. (Folder 20)
  - Deed given by Benjamin S. Ewell and his sister Elizabeth S. Ewell, to William Stoddert, September 1883. (Folder 20)
    The deed covers a tract of land called Stony Lonesome and woodland on the Rock Smith Farm in Prince William County, Virginia. The deed is not signed by Elizabeth S. Ewell.
  - Ewell(Charlotte), 3 March 1824., 1 item. (Folder 21)
    Power of attorney given by Charlotte Ewell to her brother, William Ewell, authorizing him to manage his property held by her as trustee.
  - Ewell (Elizabeth), mother of Benjamin S. Ewell, 14 May 1846., 1 item. (Folder 21)
    Deed given by Elizabeth Ewell, widow of Thomas Ewell, et al., of Prince William County, to Alexander Spotswood Grigsby, covering two lots in Centreville, Fairfax County, Virginia.
  - Ewell (Elizabeth S.), sister of Benjamin S. Ewell, 4 May 1885., 1 item. (Folder 21)
    Draft of deed granting to Benjamin S. Ewell and William Stoddert her interest in a tract of land in Prince William County, Virginia.
  - Ewell (Rebecca Lowndes), July 1860-August 1867. (Folder 21)
    - Will of Rebecca L. Ewell, 9 July 1860., 1 item. (Folder 21)
    - Agreement of Elizabeth S. Ewell, R. S. Ewell, William Stoddert, and Benjamin S. Ewell to carry into effect the will of Rebecca Lowndes Ewell, that was declared invalid by the court, 2 August 1867., 1 item. (Folder 21)
  - Ewell (Richard S.), brother of Benjamin S. Ewell, June 1863-February 1914. (Folder 21)
    - A copy of an article in the Richmond Examiner, 15 June 1863., 1 item. (Folder 21)
      The article concerns Richard S. Ewell's part in the second capture of Winchester, with a note by H. S. Turner.
    - Copy of General Richard Ewell's and General Kershaw's account of the burning of Richmond, dated Spring Hill, Tennessee, 20 December 1865., 1 item. (Folder 21)
      Includes a note by Campbell Brown dated 6 November 1873.
    - Richard S. Ewell, 7 February 1914., 1 item. (Folder 21)
      A poem written by Dr. H. M. Clarkson for the Ewell centennial celebration held at Manassas, Virginia, by the Ewell Camp of Confederate Veterans.
    - A short sketch of General Richard Ewell., 1 item. (Folder 21)
  - Ewell (Thomas), father of Benjamin S. Ewell, 1821. (Folder 21)
    - Plat of a tract of land in Prince William County, Virginia, surveyed for Dr. Thomas Ewell, 1821., 1 item. (Folder 21)
    - Apothecary's scales used by Dr. Thomas Ewell, surgeon, in the War of 1812. (Folder 21)
  - Gantt (Benjamin Stoddert)., 1 item. (Folder 21)
    Copy of a notice in the National Intelligencer announcing the death of Benjamin Stoddert Ewell.
  - Lowndes (F.), 1805-1859., 3 items. (Folder 21)
    Accounts.
  - Lowndes (Francis, 1869., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 21)
    Account of Richard P. Jackson, executor of Francis Lowndes.
  - Madison (James), president of the United States, 3 September 1819., 1 item. (Folder 21)
    Extract from a letter written by President James Madison to Mr. Edward Coles.
  - Mason family data., 1 item.
  - Neale family data., 1 item.